<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<root version="3.3" release="1|3.5E:17|CoreRPG:4">
	<battle>
		<id-00001>
			<public />
			<exp type="number">0</exp>
			<level type="number">0</level>
			<name type="string">[RESULT] Random Encounter In DarkMoon Vale</name>
			<npclist>
				<public />
			</npclist>
		</id-00001>
	</battle>
	<calendar>
		<public />
		<base>
			<public />
		</base>
		<current>
			<public />
			<day type="number">0</day>
			<month type="number">0</month>
			<year type="number">0</year>
		</current>
		<data>
			<public />
			<complete type="number">1</complete>
			<lunardaycalc type="string">gregorian</lunardaycalc>
			<lunarweek>
				<public />
				<day1 type="string">Sunday</day1>
				<day2 type="string">Moonday</day2>
				<day3 type="string">Toilday</day3>
				<day4 type="string">Wealday</day4>
				<day5 type="string">Oathday</day5>
				<day6 type="string">Fireday</day6>
				<day7 type="string">Starday</day7>
			</lunarweek>
			<name type="string">Calendar of Golarion</name>
			<periods>
				<public />
				<period1>
					<public />
					<days type="number">31</days>
					<holidays>
						<public />
						<holiday1>
							<public />
							<duration type="number">1</duration>
							<name type="string">New Year</name>
							<startday type="number">1</startday>
						</holiday1>
					</holidays>
					<name type="string">Abadius</name>
				</period1>
				<period10>
					<public />
					<days type="number">31</days>
					<name type="string">Lamashan</name>
				</period10>
				<period11>
					<public />
					<days type="number">30</days>
					<holidays>
						<public />
						<holiday1>
							<public />
							<duration type="number">1</duration>
							<name type="string">Seven Veils</name>
							<startday type="number">23</startday>
						</holiday1>
					</holidays>
					<name type="string">Neth</name>
				</period11>
				<period12>
					<public />
					<days type="number">31</days>
					<holidays>
						<public />
						<holiday1>
							<public />
							<duration type="number">1</duration>
							<name type="string">Night of the Pale</name>
							<startday type="number">31</startday>
						</holiday1>
					</holidays>
					<name type="string">Kuthona</name>
				</period12>
				<period2>
					<public />
					<days type="number">28</days>
					<holidays>
						<public />
						<holiday1>
							<public />
							<duration type="number">1</duration>
							<name type="string">Merrymead</name>
							<startday type="number">2</startday>
						</holiday1>
					</holidays>
					<name type="string">Calistril</name>
				</period2>
				<period3>
					<public />
					<days type="number">31</days>
					<name type="string">Pharast</name>
				</period3>
				<period4>
					<public />
					<days type="number">30</days>
					<name type="string">Gozran</name>
				</period4>
				<period5>
					<public />
					<days type="number">31</days>
					<name type="string">Desnus</name>
				</period5>
				<period6>
					<public />
					<days type="number">30</days>
					<name type="string">Sarenith</name>
				</period6>
				<period7>
					<public />
					<days type="number">31</days>
					<name type="string">Erastus</name>
				</period7>
				<period8>
					<public />
					<days type="number">31</days>
					<name type="string">Arodus</name>
				</period8>
				<period9>
					<public />
					<days type="number">30</days>
					<name type="string">Rova</name>
				</period9>
			</periods>
			<periodvarcalc type="string">gregorian</periodvarcalc>
			<setting type="string">Pathfinder</setting>
		</data>
	</calendar>
	<charsheet>
	</charsheet>
	<class>
	</class>
	<combattracker>
		<public />
	</combattracker>
	<currencies>
		<public />
		<id-00001>
			<public />
			<name type="string">PP</name>
		</id-00001>
		<id-00002>
			<public />
			<name type="string">GP</name>
		</id-00002>
		<id-00003>
			<public />
			<name type="string">SP</name>
		</id-00003>
		<id-00004>
			<public />
			<name type="string">CP</name>
		</id-00004>
	</currencies>
	<effects>
		<public />
	</effects>
	<encounter>
		<id-00001>
			<public />
			<name type="string">[RESULT] Random Encounter In DarkMoon Vale</name>
			<text type="formattedtext">
				<list>
					<li>Foul Tracks</li>
				</list>
			</text>
		</id-00001>
		<id-00002>
			<name type="string">[RESULT] Random Encounter In DarkMoon Vale</name>
			<text type="formattedtext">
				<list>
					<li>Dead Fey</li>
				</list>
			</text>
		</id-00002>
		<category name="Hollow's Last Hope" baseicon="0" decalicon="0">
			<id-00003>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Introduction</name>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<p>Any number of events might draw the PCs to the small trade town of Falcon&#146;s Hollow. Merchant caravans regularly travel here from any number of points abroad, trading for the rare darkwood that grows so abundantly in Darkmoon Vale, and potentially bringing exotic individuals to town as guards or paying travelers. Alternatively, characters might be long-time residents of Falcon&#146;s Hollow, young or adventurous souls seeking excitement and opportunity beyond the lumber mills and town&#146;s petty intrigues. Local residents might already know one another as friends or relations, or they might encounter one another as they&#146;re individually drawn to seek a cure for the town&#146;s affliction (likely either in line at Roots and Remedies or at Laurel&#146;s suggestion of cooperation).</p>
					<p>If the PCs need encouragement to become involved in the plot of the adventure, a friend, relative, or possibly one of the PCs themselves might come down with blackscour taint. Alternatively, both herbalist Laurel and Sheriff Baleson could put out calls for assistance, drawing on PCs&#146; specific talents, which might lead the PCs to learn of Laurel&#146;s more unusual cure.</p>
					<p>When you&#146;re ready to begin the adventure, read or paraphrase the following to the players.</p>
					<frame>Perched at the edge of civilized lands, the small town of Falcon&#146;s Hollow has always had to rely on itself to solve its problems. Meanwhile, the uncaring lumber barons squeeze the common folk for every last copper, deaf to their pleas. Now the hacking coughs of the sick are heard throughout town. The plague has come to Falcon&#146;s Hollow and the town&#146;s leaders can&#146;t be bothered to stop it.</frame>
					<p><b>The Town of Falcon&#146;s Hollow</b></p>
					<linklist>
						<link class="note" recordname="notes.id-00003">Falcons Hollow Note</link>
						<link class="imagewindow" recordname="image.id-00003">Falcons Hollow Map</link>
					</linklist>
					<p>A rough community wholly owned by the local Lumber Consortium, Falcon&#146;s Hollow rests on the edge of Darkmoon Vale, a blunt, sawdust-choked stop on a winding trade route. Home to fewer than 1,500 humans and a smattering of other races, most of the townsfolk care only for the paltry coins paid for their backbreaking work and what simple comforts they can buy. A few, however, understand that what&#146;s bad for one is bad for all, and so the community thrives on a tenacious mix of greed, debauchery, and stubborn self-reliance.</p>
					<linklist>
						<link class="encounter" recordname="encounter.id-00004">The Affliction</link>
					</linklist>
				</text>
			</id-00003>
			<id-00004>
				<name type="string">The Affliction</name>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<p>The Affliction At the start of this adventure, several dozen people in Falcon&#146;s Hollow have contracted a fungal disease called blackscour taint. While the malady is not exceptionally deadly, poor conditions and a general lack of supplies mean that many of the sick&#151;especially the elderly and young&#151;face mortal consequences. Slowly deteriorating, most of the afflicted can hang on for several more days, but already the weakest have succumbed, with their number growing daily. Blackscour taint is an ingested disease with an incubation period of 1d3 days. The disease deals 1d2 points of Constitution damage and is resisted with a DC 14 Fortitude save. Those who are infected develop a hacking cough that quickly turns bloody if the disease is allowed to progress. For the first two days from the start of the adventure, 1d4 townsfolk die from blackscour taint every day. On the third day, 2d4 townsfolk die, then 3d4 on the fourth day, with the death toll increasing an additional 1d4 every day until a total of forty villagers have perished. If the PCs have acquaintances or loved ones afflicted by blackscour taint (and who lack full NPC statistics), roll 4d10 for each noteworthy relation. If the PCs do not return to town with a cure for the disease by the time the death toll reaches the NPC&#146;s number, the specified character dies. Once forty townsfolk die from blackscour taint, the malady has run its course, killing all those unable to overcome the disease on their own. If the PCs take up the search for a cure and fail to return to Falcon&#146;s Hollow by this time, they are widely shunned and blamed by many for the deaths of their loved ones.</p>
					<linklist>
						<link class="encounter" recordname="encounter.id-00005">Part 1: An Elusive Antidote</link>
					</linklist>
				</text>
			</id-00004>
			<id-00005>
				<name type="string">Part 1: An Elusive Antidote</name>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<p>Falcon&#146;s Hollow has few clerics, and only <b>Lady Cirthana </b>(LG female cleric 2 of Iomedae) shows any interest in stopping the illness and she lacks the ability to cure diseases. Since few townsfolk trust her, most lay their medical concerns at the feet of the local herbalist, a tough woman named <b>Laurel </b>(NG female human expert 3), whose income stems as much from her sale of snake oils and aphrodisiacs as from questionable cure-alls and bitter teas. As quick to suggest expensive remedies as she is to remind angry buyers that she is not, in fact, a physician, Laurel does her best to help those who come to her in need, but her tight income, need to survive, and pride prevent her from admitting failure.</p>
					<p>In treating the blackscour taint, as in most cases, Laurel has turned to her grandmother&#146;s tome of recipes, cures, and spells for aid. Although the book contains no actual magic, it holds the rooted wisdom of generations of Laurel&#146;s family, including the teachings of the Witch of Darkmoon Vale, Ulizmila, from whom Laurel&#146;s grandmother learned in exchange for her sight. There&#146;s one last treatment from the cultic appendices of the tome&#151;scribed in a hand that is not Laurel&#146;s grandmother&#146;s&#151;that the herbalist has yet to try, as she lacks three of the most important ingredients and would rather do what she can for the sick with what she knows than chase a fanciful salvation.</p>
					<p>How the PCs come to entreat Laurel for aid is largely up to the GM. A <b>DC 10 Knowledge (local) </b>check or merely inquiring with any of the families of the afflicted reveals that Laurel is aiding the families of the sick as best she can&#151;although her proscriptions are little more than bed rest and a pungent black urdroot tea. Nearly anyone in town can direct the PCs to Laurel&#146;s shop, the unmistakably named Roots and Remedies. The line stemming from Laurel&#146;s shop makes a useful first-time meeting place for unacquainted PCs.</p>
					<linklist>
						<link class="encounter" recordname="encounter.id-00006">Roots and Remedies</link>
						<link class="encounter" recordname="encounter.id-00007">Roots and Remedies ( Laurel Q&#38;A )</link>
					</linklist>
				</text>
			</id-00005>
			<id-00006>
				<name type="string">Roots and Remedies</name>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<frame>Creeping ivy and full window boxes cover the fa&#231;ade of the rugged-looking, two-story shop bearing the faded sign &#147;Roots and Remedies.&#148; A line of twenty-some somber townsfolk&#151;some with pale, wheezing children, others seeming to be precipitously near tears&#151;stretches from the open door.</frame>
					<p>Laurel&#146;s shop has been besieged since the outbreak of blackscour taint, both by the afflicted and their families and by hypochondriacs of all stripes. While she tries to help those with legitimate concerns as best she can, she has no qualms in selling the deluded her most expensive balms.</p>
					<p>Unless the PCs attempt to bypass the line&#151;an act that might touch off a small, hacking riot&#151;it takes nearly an hour to reach the door of Roots and Remedies. Once inside, the clutter and disrepair of the shop shows the recent traffic, and Laurel visibly overworks herself at the store&#146;s rear, brewing remedies for the ill.</p>
					<frame>The smell of burnt earth and spicy incense chokes the air of the cramped, mud-tracked shop. Bunches of dried herbs hang from the ceiling, along with dangling pots, presses, alchemical apparatuses, and glassware of more arcane purposes. Pouches of rare plants, jars of colored glass, and all manner of dried, preserved, and jellied animal parts fill high shelves and tables doing double duty as displays and workspaces. In the shop&#146;s rear, a rail-thin woman with severe-looking spectacles and hair pulled back tightly busies herself between an overpacked rack of herbs, a table covered in stray powders and measuring equipment, and a pot loudly bubbling over with thick gray froth. Over the din of her work and without looking up, the woman impatiently shouts, &#147;And what&#146;s your problem?&#148;</frame>
					<p>The PCs are free to converse with Laurel as they please and she can tell them anything they need to know about the blackscour outbreak, how many people are afflicted, and&#151;especially&#151;how it&#146;s not her job to treat every cut and scabbed knee the daft people of Falcon&#146;s Hollow come crying to her about.</p>
					<p>Initially dismissive if the PCs don&#146;t present themselves as customers or capable assistants, she eventually comes around and tells the PCs what she knows about the taint. Even if the PCs seem honestly willing to help, she might not even think to mention the untried medicine until the characters are about to walk out the door, calling them back at the last moment.</p>
					<p>While conversing with Laurel, she answers some of the most likely questions as follows:</p>
					<linklist>
						<link class="imagewindow" recordname="image.id-00012">Laurel</link>
						<link class="encounter" recordname="encounter.id-00007">Roots and Remedies ( Laurel Q&#38;A )</link>
					</linklist>
				</text>
			</id-00006>
			<id-00007>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Roots and Remedies ( Laurel Q&#38;A )</name>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<p><b>What is blackscour?</b></p>
					<frame>&#147;Just a fungus that&#146;s not good for anything. Hard, bitter, and sharp, it likes the water and gets you sick if you drink it down. Never heard of it growing around these parts, though, until now.&#148;</frame>
					<p><b>What is blackscour taint?</b></p>
					<frame>&#147;It&#146;s a sickness, almost like any other, but you get the mold growing in you. It starts eating away in your chest and belly and is damned determined to stay. Your body near turns itself insideout trying to hack the stuff up, but all that does is cuts your guts up&#133; bad.&#148;</frame>
					<p><b>How many townsfolk have blackscour taint?</b></p>
					<frame>&#147;More than thirty, honestly, though at least three times that thinks they&#146;ve got it.&#148;</frame>
					<p><b>Is there any cure?</b></p>
					<frame>&#147;Not around here. I&#146;ll get these folks what I can and we&#146;ll see what good it does.&#148;</frame>
					<p><b>There&#146;s another medicine?</b></p>
					<frame>&#147;My grandmother&#146;s book has a brew in it that says its good for this kind of thing. A weird concoction that sounds more like hoojoo than real medicine.&#148;</frame>
					<p><b>What&#146;s in this medicine?</b></p>
					<frame>&#147;Some rare roots and concentrations, most of which I have here, but there&#146;s three I don&#146;t. Elderwood moss, which I&#146;ve never heard of, but granny says the stuff only grows on the oldest tree in a forest. A specially pickled root called rat&#146;s tail, again, sounds like hoojoo to me. And seven ironbloom mushrooms, stunty little things that only grow in dark places thick with metal, a favorite among dwarves, or so I hear.&#148;</frame>
					<p><b>Do you know where we could find these ingredients?</b></p>
					<frame>&#147;Well, for the elderwood mold, there&#146;s gotta be an oldest tree in the vale. Damned if I know where it is, though. &#147;The rat&#146;s tail and mushrooms are even longer shots. Way north, toward the mountains, people say there used to live a bunch of dwarves. They&#146;re not there anymore, but I&#146;d bet their forges are. If you can find ironbloom anywhere around here, that&#146;d be your best bet. &#147;As for the rat&#146;s tail, who knows? Well. Actually. Ulizmila, the witch that lives deep in the woods might. She&#146;s a crafty, mean thing that knows all sorts of strangeness. She might even have one. I don&#146;t know what she might want for it, but I doubt it&#146;d come cheap. My grandmother traded her sight to the old crone for a few pages of what she knew, and that was years and years back, and I don&#146;t know a soul who got any nicer as they got older.&#148;</frame>
					<p><b>How much time do we have to get the ingredients?</b></p>
					<p>&#147;None! Folks are dying every day! All we can hope to do now is treat who we can and hope to save the gravedigger some work.&#148;</p>
					<p><b>Can you pay us for finding these ingredients? [Outraged]</b></p>
					<frame>&#147;Pay you!? I&#146;ll pay you in&#133;! Well, I suppose I&#146;m not doing all this for free either. If nothing else, this whole thing&#146;s been good for business. How about this, you come back with everything I need to brew the medicine and I&#146;ll cut you in: thirty gold each. Fair?&#148;</frame>
					<p>She can be bargained up to 45 gp each with a successful DC 15 Diplomacy check. Although Laurel has an idea of where the ingredients for her medicine might be found, she&#146;s never set foot beyond the fringes of Darkmoon Vale and honestly has no idea where the locations she mentions are. If the PCs seem committed to searching, she suggests they head to the Consortium Lumber Camp to the east and look for Milon Rhoddam&#151; the most experienced woodsman in the Lumber Consortium.</p>
				</text>
			</id-00007>
		</category>
	</encounter>
	<feat>
		<category name="Hollow's Last Hope" baseicon="0" decalicon="0">
			<id-00001>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p></p>
				</benefit>
				<flavor type="string">Improved Grab</flavor>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Improved Grab</name>
				<normal type="formattedtext">
					<p></p>
				</normal>
				<special type="formattedtext">
					<p></p>
				</special>
				<summary type="string">To use this ability, a creature must hit a Medium or smaller foe with its bite attack. It can then attempt to start a grapple as a free action without provoking an attack of opportunity. If it wins the grapple check, it establishes a hold.</summary>
				<type type="string">Ex</type>
			</id-00001>
			<id-00002>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>contact; DC 12 Con; initial 1 Con; secondary ;</p>
				</benefit>
				<flavor type="string">Poison Grasp</flavor>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Posion Grasp</name>
				<normal type="formattedtext">
					<p></p>
				</normal>
				<special type="formattedtext">
					<p></p>
				</special>
				<summary type="string">A tatzlwyrm&#146;s breath is poisonous, but not very powerful. While grappling, instead of making a bite or rake attack, a tatzlwyrm can breathe its poison into its victim&#146;s face.\nA tatzlywyrm must begin its turn\ngrappling to use this ability&#151;it can&#146;t begin a grapple and use its poison gasp in the same turn.</summary>
				<type type="string">Ex</type>
			</id-00002>
		</category>
	</feat>
	<image>
		<category name="Hollow's Last Hope" baseicon="0" decalicon="0">
			<id-00001>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/Dark Moon Vale Map(DM).jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<name type="string">Dark Moon Vale Map(DM)</name>
			</id-00001>
			<id-00002>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/Droskars Crucible.jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<name type="string">Droskars Crucible</name>
			</id-00002>
			<id-00003>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/Falcons Hollow.jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<name type="string">Falcons Hollow</name>
				<nonid_name type="string">FAlcons Hollow Locations</nonid_name>
			</id-00003>
			<id-00004>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/Graypelt.jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<name type="string">Graypelt</name>
			</id-00004>
			<id-00005>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/Hollows Last Hope.jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<name type="string">Hollows Last Hope</name>
			</id-00005>
			<id-00006>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/Dark Moon Vale Map(PC).jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<isidentified type="number">1</isidentified>
				<name type="string">Dark Moon Vale Map(PC)</name>
				<nonid_name type="string">Falcons Hollow Environs</nonid_name>
			</id-00006>
			<id-00007>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/Monastery.jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<name type="string">Monastery</name>
			</id-00007>
			<id-00008>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/Ring Of Torag.jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<name type="string">Ring Of Torag</name>
			</id-00008>
			<id-00009>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/SoulSpeaker.jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<name type="string">SoulSpeaker</name>
			</id-00009>
			<id-00010>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/tatzlwyrm.jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<name type="string">tatzlwyrm</name>
			</id-00010>
			<id-00011>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/Lady Cirthana.jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<name type="string">Lady Cirthana</name>
			</id-00011>
			<id-00012>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/Laurel.jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<name type="string">Laurel</name>
			</id-00012>
			<id-00013>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/Droskars Crucible(PC).jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<name type="string">Droskars Crucible(PC)</name>
			</id-00013>
			<id-00014>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/giantmoorsnake.jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<name type="string">giantmoorsnake</name>
			</id-00014>
			<id-00015>
				<image type="image">
					<bitmap>images/Giant Mosquito.jpg</bitmap>
				</image>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Giant Mosquito</name>
			</id-00015>
		</category>
	</image>
	<item>
	</item>
	<languages>
		<public />
		<id-00001>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Elven</font>
			<name type="string">Aquan</name>
		</id-00001>
		<id-00002>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Dwarven</font>
			<name type="string">Orc</name>
		</id-00002>
		<id-00003>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Celestial</font>
			<name type="string">Celestial</name>
		</id-00003>
		<id-00004>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Infernal</font>
			<name type="string">Infernal</name>
		</id-00004>
		<id-00005>
			<public />
			<name type="string">Gnoll</name>
		</id-00005>
		<id-00006>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Elven</font>
			<name type="string">Elven</name>
		</id-00006>
		<id-00007>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Draconic</font>
			<name type="string">Ignan</name>
		</id-00007>
		<id-00008>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Elven</font>
			<name type="string">Undercommon</name>
		</id-00008>
		<id-00009>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Draconic</font>
			<name type="string">Draconic</name>
		</id-00009>
		<id-00010>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Infernal</font>
			<name type="string">Abyssal</name>
		</id-00010>
		<id-00011>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Elven</font>
			<name type="string">Sylvan</name>
		</id-00011>
		<id-00012>
			<public />
			<name type="string">Aklo</name>
		</id-00012>
		<id-00013>
			<public />
			<name type="string">Common</name>
		</id-00013>
		<id-00014>
			<public />
			<name type="string">Vishkanya</name>
		</id-00014>
		<id-00015>
			<public />
			<name type="string">Vanaran</name>
		</id-00015>
		<id-00016>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Dwarven</font>
			<name type="string">Gnome</name>
		</id-00016>
		<id-00017>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Dwarven</font>
			<name type="string">Dwarven</name>
		</id-00017>
		<id-00018>
			<public />
			<name type="string">Grippli</name>
		</id-00018>
		<id-00019>
			<public />
			<name type="string">Catfolk</name>
		</id-00019>
		<id-00020>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Dwarven</font>
			<name type="string">Terran</name>
		</id-00020>
		<id-00021>
			<public />
			<name type="string">Halfling</name>
		</id-00021>
		<id-00022>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Dwarven</font>
			<name type="string">Goblin</name>
		</id-00022>
		<id-00023>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Dwarven</font>
			<name type="string">Giant</name>
		</id-00023>
		<id-00024>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Draconic</font>
			<name type="string">Auran</name>
		</id-00024>
		<id-00025>
			<public />
			<font type="string">Elven</font>
			<name type="string">Druidic</name>
		</id-00025>
	</languages>
	<library>
	</library>
	<modifiers>
		<public />
	</modifiers>
	<notes>
		<id-00001>
			<name type="string">Pathfinder chronicals Falcons Hollow</name>
			<text type="formattedtext">
				<p>The small village of Falcon&#146;s Hollow is a wild place. Nestled in the shadow of Droskar&#146;s Crag, the people of Falcon&#146;s Hollow are hearty and stern. Theirs is a life of hardships, broken only occasionally by a handful of festivals and the infrequent merchant caravan. They face constant adversity from both the wilderness and the wiles of man. Wolves nip at their heels and cutpurses ply at their pockets. It is a testament to their strength that they even manage to survive at all. &#151;Pathfinder Chronicles</p>
			</text>
		</id-00001>
		<id-00003>
			<locked type="number">1</locked>
			<name type="string">Falcons Hollow Note</name>
			<text type="formattedtext">
				<p><b>Town </b>nonstandard (Lumber Consortium);</p>
				<p><b>AL </b>NE</p>
				<p><b>GP Limit </b>1,500 gp;</p>
				<p><b>Assets </b>40,550 gp</p>
				<p><b>DEMOGRAPHICS</b></p>
				<p><b>Population </b>1,400</p>
				<p><b>Type </b>isolated (human 94%, halfling 3%, half-elf 1%, elf 1%, other 1% )</p>
				<p><b>AUTHORITY FIGURES</b></p>
				<p><b>Gavel Thuldrin Kreed </b>, LE male human expert 3/ rogue 4 (Gavel of the Lumber Consortium), <b>Magistrate Vamros Harg </b>, NE male halfling aristocrat 2/sorcerer 5 (Magistrate-Elect), <b>Sheriff Deldrin Baleson </b>, LN male halfelf expert 3/fighter 3 (Sheriff of Darkmoon Vale), <b>Boss Payden &#147;Pay Day&#148; Teedum </b>, LE male human monk 2/fighter 3 (Overboss of the Lumber Consortium).</p>
				<p></p>
				<linklist>
					<link class="imagewindow" recordname="image.id-00003">Falcons Hollow Map</link>
				</linklist>
			</text>
		</id-00003>
		<id-00004>
			<locked type="number">1</locked>
			<name type="string">Before The Kobold King</name>
			<text type="formattedtext">
				<p>Aside from being its own adventure, <i>Hollow&#146;s Last Hope </i>works well as a prelude to GameMastery Module <i>D1: Crown of the Kobold King </i>. GMs interested in running this adventure as part of <i>Crown of the Kobold King </i>can remove all elements of the disease afflicting Falcon&#146;s Hollow and instead use the encounters in Darkmoon Vale and in the ruins above the kobolds&#146; lair as supplementary encounters. Containing its own complete adventure and extensive details on the town of Falcon&#146;s Hollow, Nicolas Logue&#146;s <i>Crown of the Kobold King</i></p>
			</text>
		</id-00004>
		<id-00006>
			<locked type="number">1</locked>
			<name type="string">Mapping the Vale</name>
			<text type="formattedtext">
				<p>At some point, the PCs are going to need to determine where in Darkmoon Vale to search for the ingredients to create Laurel&#146;s cure. Of greatest interest are: Ulizmila&#146;s hut, the oldest tree in the vale, and the dwarven ruins. PCs familiar with the area might be able to make the following Knowledge checks to know where these sites lie. If they lack these skills, the PCs can question Milon Rhoddam at the Consortium Lumber Camp.</p>
				<p><b>Location Knowledge Check and DC</b></p>
				<p>Ulizmila&#146;s Hut Geography DC 16, Local DC 20</p>
				<p>Eldest Tree Geography DC 20, Nature DC 24</p>
				<p>Dwarven Monastary Geography DC 16, Local DC 20</p>
			</text>
		</id-00006>
	</notes>
	<npc>
		<category name="Hollow's Last Hope" baseicon="0" decalicon="0">
			<id-00001>
				<atk type="string">2d6 fall damage, DC 20 Reflex avoids; multiple targets</atk>
				<charisma type="number">10</charisma>
				<constitution type="number">10</constitution>
				<cr type="number">1</cr>
				<dexterity type="number">10</dexterity>
				<fortitudesave type="number">0</fortitudesave>
				<hp type="number">0</hp>
				<init type="number">0</init>
				<intelligence type="number">10</intelligence>
				<isidentified type="number">1</isidentified>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Pit trap</name>
				<nonid_name type="string">Pit Trap</nonid_name>
				<npctype type="string">Trap</npctype>
				<reflexsave type="number">0</reflexsave>
				<reset type="string">manual</reset>
				<senses type="string">Perception DC 20; Disable Device DC 20</senses>
				<spelldisplaymode type="string">action</spelldisplaymode>
				<spellset>
				</spellset>
				<strength type="number">10</strength>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<p></p>
				</text>
				<token type="token">tokens/Medium/t.png@Letter Tokens</token>
				<trigger type="string">location</trigger>
				<type type="string">mechanical</type>
				<willsave type="number">0</willsave>
				<wisdom type="number">10</wisdom>
			</id-00001>
			<id-00002>
				<ac type="string">16, touch 16, flat-footed 12 (+4 Dex, +2 size)</ac>
				<alignment type="string">N</alignment>
				<atk type="string">touch +7 (attach)</atk>
				<babgrp type="string">Base Atk +1; CMB +3 (+11 grapple when attached); CMD 9 (17 vs. trip)</babgrp>
				<charisma type="number">6</charisma>
				<constitution type="number">10</constitution>
				<cr type="number">0.5</cr>
				<dexterity type="number">19</dexterity>
				<environment type="string">temperate and warm swamps</environment>
				<feats type="string">Weapon Finesse</feats>
				<fortitudesave type="number">2</fortitudesave>
				<fullatk type="string">touch +7 (attach)</fullatk>
				<hd type="string">1d10</hd>
				<hp type="number">5</hp>
				<init type="number">4</init>
				<intelligence type="number">1</intelligence>
				<isidentified type="number">1</isidentified>
				<librarylink type="windowreference">
					<class>npc</class>
					<recordname>..</recordname>
				</librarylink>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Giant Mosquito</name>
				<nonid_name type="string">Giant Mosquito</nonid_name>
				<organization type="string">solitary, colony (2-4), flock (5-8), storm (9-14), or swarm (15-40)</organization>
				<reflexsave type="number">6</reflexsave>
				<senses type="string">darkvision 60 ft., low-light vision, scent; Perception +1</senses>
				<skills type="string">Fly +8, Stealth +16</skills>
				<spacereach type="string">2ft./0ft.</spacereach>
				<specialabilities>
					<attach-ex>
						<locked type="number">1</locked>
						<name type="string">Attach (Ex)</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>When a stirge hits with a touch attack, its barbed legs latch onto the target, anchoring it in place. An attached stirge is effectively grappling its prey. The stirge loses its Dexterity bonus to AC and has an AC of 12, but holds on with great tenacity and inserts its proboscis into the grappled target's flesh. A stirge has a +8 racial bonus to maintain its grapple on a foe once it is attached. An attached stirge can be struck with a weapon or grappled itself-if its prey manages to win a grapple check or Escape Artist check against it, the stirge is removed.</p>
						</text>
					</attach-ex>
					<blooddrain-ex>
						<locked type="number">1</locked>
						<name type="string">Blood Drain (Ex)</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>A stirge drains blood at the end of its turn if it is attached to a foe, inflicting 1 point of Constitution damage. Once a stirge has dealt 4 points of Constitution damage, it detaches and flies off to digest the meal. If its victim dies before the stirge's appetite has been sated, the stirge detaches and seeks a new target.</p>
						</text>
					</blooddrain-ex>
					<diseased-ex>
						<name type="string">Diseased (Ex)</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Due to the stagnant swamps in which they live and their contact with the blood of numerous creatures, stirges are harbingers of disease. Any creature subjected to a stirge's blood drain attack has a 10% chance of being exposed to filth fever, blinding sickness, or a similar disease (Pathfinder RPG Core Rulebook 557). Once this check is made, the victim can no longer be infected by this particular stirge, though attacks by different stirges are resolved normally and may result in multiple illnesses.</p>
						</text>
					</diseased-ex>
				</specialabilities>
				<specialattacks type="string">blood drain</specialattacks>
				<specialqualities type="string">diseased</specialqualities>
				<speed type="string">10 ft., fly 40 ft. (average)</speed>
				<spelldisplaymode type="string">action</spelldisplaymode>
				<strength type="number">3</strength>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<linklist>
						<link class="imagewindow" recordname="image.id-00015">Giant Mosquito</link>
					</linklist>
					<frame>This insectoid creature has two pairs of bat wings, a tangle of thin legs, and a needle-sharp proboscis.</frame>
					<p>This creature will flee if it takes any damage.</p>
					<p></p>
					<h>Special Abilities</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="..specialabilities.attach-ex">Attach (Ex)</link>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="..specialabilities.blooddrain-ex">Blood Drain (Ex)</link>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="..specialabilities.diseased-ex">Diseased (Ex)</link>
					</linklist>
					<h>Other Abilities**</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.darkvision@*">Darkvision 60 ft.</link>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.lowlightvision@*">Low-light vision</link>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.scent@*">Scent</link>
					</linklist>
					<h>Feats**</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referencefeat" recordname="reference.feats.weaponfinesse@*">Weapon Finesse.</link>
					</linklist>
					<p>Stirges are vicious, blood-drinking swamp pests that prey on wild animals, livestock, and unwary travelers. While weak individually, swarms of the creatures are capable of draining a man dry in minutes, leaving only a desiccated husk in their wake.</p>
					<p>Closer to mammals than insects, stirges carry their bodies through the air on four fleshy wings, searching out warm-blooded prey. They are fond of hiding near watering holes and waiting for travelers to drop their guard, then swooping out to attach and drink their fill by thrusting their long feeding tubes into unprotected veins. After feeding they flap heavily off into the mud and reeds to lay their eggs and rest until hunger drives them to hunt again.</p>
					<p>Stirges are usually 1 foot long, with a wingspan of twice that, and weigh just under a pound. Their coloration is rust-red or reddish-brown with a dirty yellow underbelly, though stirges that have not fed in some time are often pale pink, their color deepening as they gorge.</p>
					<p><b><u>End Note: </u></b><b>** </b>- These links reference Fantasy Grounds library modules - <b><i>Other Abilities </i></b>are links to Universal Monster Rules in a Bestiary Module, and <b><i>Feats </i></b>are links to Core/Basic Rules modules. Relevant modules must be activated for these links to operate.</p>
				</text>
				<token type="token">campaign/tokens/giantmosquito.png</token>
				<treasure type="string">none</treasure>
				<type type="string">N Tiny Insect</type>
				<willsave type="number">1</willsave>
				<wisdom type="number">12</wisdom>
				<xp type="number">200</xp>
			</id-00002>
			<id-00004>
				<ac type="string">15, touch 13, flat-footed 12 (+3 Dex, +2 natural)</ac>
				<alignment type="string">N</alignment>
				<atk type="string">bite +5 (1d4+4 plus grab)</atk>
				<babgrp type="string">Base Atk +2; CMB +5 (+9 grapple); CMD 18 (can't be tripped)</babgrp>
				<charisma type="number">2</charisma>
				<constitution type="number">12</constitution>
				<cr type="number">2</cr>
				<dexterity type="number">17</dexterity>
				<environment type="string">warm forests, swamps, and fresh water</environment>
				<feats type="string">Skill Focus (Perception), Toughness</feats>
				<fortitudesave type="number">4</fortitudesave>
				<fullatk type="string">bite +5 (1d4+4 plus grab)</fullatk>
				<hd type="string">3d8+6</hd>
				<hp type="number">19</hp>
				<init type="number">3</init>
				<intelligence type="number">1</intelligence>
				<librarylink type="windowreference">
					<class>npc</class>
					<recordname>..</recordname>
				</librarylink>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Snake, Giant Moor</name>
				<nonid_name type="string">Giant Snake</nonid_name>
				<organization type="string">solitary or nest (2-6)</organization>
				<reflexsave type="number">6</reflexsave>
				<senses type="string">scent; Perception +12</senses>
				<skills type="string">Acrobatics +15, Climb +11, Perception +12, Stealth +11, Swim +11; Racial Modifiers +4 Perception, +4 Stealth, +8 Acrobatics</skills>
				<spacereach type="string">5ft./5ft.</spacereach>
				<specialattacks type="string">constrict (1d4+4)</specialattacks>
				<speed type="string">20 ft., climb 20 ft., swim 20 ft.</speed>
				<spelldisplaymode type="string">action</spelldisplaymode>
				<spellset>
				</spellset>
				<strength type="number">17</strength>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<linklist>
						<link class="imagewindow" recordname="image.id-00014">Giant Moorsnake</link>
					</linklist>
					<p>This large snake has a thick, muscular body and black scales decorated with dirty green stripes.</p>
					<p>During the day, the moorsnake is too lethargic to attack and merely slithers away. At night, though, it might slip into camp and attempt to constrict a sleeping PC.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p><b>Other Abilities*</b>*</p>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.scent@*">Scent</link>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.constrict@*">Constrict (1d4+4)</link>
					</linklist>
					<h>Feats**</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referencefeat" recordname="reference.feats.skillfocus@*">Skill Focus (Perception)</link>
						<link class="referencefeat" recordname="reference.feats.toughness@*">Toughness.</link>
					</linklist>
					<p>Be they jungle-dwelling pythons or swampdwelling boas like the anaconda, constrictor snakes are among the most deadly predatory animals of the tropical wilds. Fortunately, these large snakes are relatively passive, save for when they are preparing to shed their skins or are particularly hungry. Nevertheless, the sinuous creatures are held in fear by many societies who often ascribe f iendish qualities to them.</p>
					<p>The constrictor snake presented here is a relatively small one. You can create stats for a larger maneater like an anaconda by applying the advanced and giant simple templates, or by advancing the stats above to a 7 HD Large snake (CR 5), or even a 14 HD Huge snake (CR 10).</p>
					<p><b><u>End Note: </u></b><b>** </b>- These links reference Fantasy Grounds library modules - <b><i>Other Abilities </i></b>are links to Universal Monster Rules in a Bestiary Module, and <b><i>Feats </i></b>are links to Core/Basic Rules modules. Relevant modules must be activated for these links to operate.</p>
				</text>
				<token type="token">campaign/tokens/giant_moorsnake.png</token>
				<treasure type="string">none</treasure>
				<type type="string">N Medium animal</type>
				<willsave type="number">2</willsave>
				<wisdom type="number">12</wisdom>
				<xp type="number">600</xp>
			</id-00004>
			<id-00005>
				<ac type="string">16, touch 12, flat-footed 14 (+3 armor, +2 Dex, +1 shield)</ac>
				<alignment type="string">LE</alignment>
				<atk type="string">longsword +4 (1d8+2/19-20) or longbow +3 ranged (1d8/x3)</atk>
				<babgrp type="string">Base Atk +1; CMB +3; CMD 15</babgrp>
				<charisma type="number">8</charisma>
				<constitution type="number">16</constitution>
				<cr type="number">0.5</cr>
				<dexterity type="number">15</dexterity>
				<environment type="string">temperate hills</environment>
				<feats type="string">Toughness, Weapon Focus (longsword)</feats>
				<fortitudesave type="number">5</fortitudesave>
				<fullatk type="string">longsword +4 (1d8+2/19-20) or longbow +3 ranged (1d8/x3)</fullatk>
				<hd type="string">1d10+7</hd>
				<hp type="number">17</hp>
				<init type="number">2</init>
				<intelligence type="number">10</intelligence>
				<languages type="string">Common, Goblin</languages>
				<librarylink type="windowreference">
					<class>npc</class>
					<recordname>..</recordname>
				</librarylink>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Grung Knifetongue</name>
				<nonid_name type="string">Hobgoblin</nonid_name>
				<organization type="string">gang (4-9), warband (10-24), or tribe (25+ plus 50% noncombatants, 1 sergeant of 3rd level per 20 adults, 1 or 2 lieutenants of 4th or 5th level, 1 leader of 6th-8th level, 6-12 leopards, and 1-4 ogres or 1-2 trolls)</organization>
				<raceclass type="string">Hobgoblin fighter 1</raceclass>
				<reflexsave type="number">2</reflexsave>
				<senses type="string">darkvision 60 ft.; Perception +2</senses>
				<skills type="string">Perception +2, Stealth +5; Racial Modifiers +4 Stealth</skills>
				<spacereach type="string">5ft./5ft.</spacereach>
				<speed type="string">30 ft.</speed>
				<spelldisplaymode type="string">action</spelldisplaymode>
				<spellset>
				</spellset>
				<strength type="number">15</strength>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<linklist>
						<link class="imagewindow" recordname="image.hobgoblin@Pathfinder Bestiary">Hobgoblin Image</link>
					</linklist>
					<frame>Standing as tall as a human, this muscular, gray-skinned creature peers about with tiny, observant eyes.</frame>
					<p><b>Race, Class and Level: </b>Hobgoblin fighter 1</p>
					<p><b>Before Combat</b> Grung hides nearby, taking 10 on his Hide check (for a total of 18 including penalties for distance). Those who fail to spot him are surprised when he attacks. </p>
					<p><b>During Combat</b> Grung has a shortbow instead of javelins and fires every round at the PCs, while his razorcrows attack. </p>
					<p><b>Morale</b> If Grung takes any amount of damage or if the PCs close to within 20 feet of him, he leaps from his perch (10 feet up in the trees) and attempts to flee.</p>
					<p></p>
					<h>Other Abilities**</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.darkvision@*">Darkvision 60 ft.</link>
					</linklist>
					<h>Feats**</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referencefeat" recordname="reference.feats.toughness@*">Toughness</link>
						<link class="referencefeat" recordname="reference.feats.weaponfocus@*">Weapon Focus (longsword).</link>
					</linklist>
					<p>Hobgoblins are militaristic and fecund, a combination that makes them quite dangerous in some regions. They breed quickly, replacing fallen members with new soldiers and keeping up their numbers despite the fortunes of war. They generally need little reason to declare war, but more often than not that reason is to capture new slaves- life as a slave in a hobgoblin lair is brutal and short, and new slaves are always needed to replace those who fall or are eaten.</p>
					<p>Of all the goblinoid races, the hobgoblin is by far the most civilized. They see the larger and more solitary bugbears as tools to be hired and used where appropriate, usually for specif ic missions involving assassination and stealth, and look upon their smaller goblin kin with a mix of shame and frustration. Hobgoblins admire goblin tenacity, yet their miniscule kindred's unpredictable nature and fondness for f ire make them unwelcome additions to hobgoblin tribes or settlements. Nonetheless, most hobgoblin tribes include a small group of goblins, typically squatting in the most undesirable corners of the settlement.</p>
					<p>Many hobgoblin tribes combine their love of warfare with keen intellects. The science of siege engines, alchemy, and complex feats of engineering fascinate most hobgoblins, and those who are particularly skilled are treated as heroes and invariably secure high-ranking positions in the tribe. Slaves with analytical minds are quite valued, and as such raids on dwarven cities are commonplace.</p>
					<p>It is well known that hobgoblins mistrust and even despise magic, particularly arcane magic. Their shamans are treated with a mix of fear and respect, and are usually forced to live alone on the fringes of the tribe's lair. It is all but unheard of to f ind a hobgoblin practicing arcane magic, or as hobgoblins call it, &#34;elf magic.&#34; This is the root of their hatred of magic-the hobgoblins' hatred of elves.</p>
					<p>A hobgoblin stands 5 feet tall and weighs 160 pounds.</p>
					<h>Hobgoblin Characters</h>
					<p>Hobgoblins are defined by their class levels-they do not possess racial Hit Dice. All hobgoblins have the following racial traits.</p>
					<p><b>+2 Dexterity, +2 Constitution: </b>Hobgoblins are fast and hearty.</p>
					<p><b>Darkvision: </b>Hobgoblins can see in the dark up to 60 feet.</p>
					<p><b>Sneaky: </b>Hobgoblins gain a +4 racial bonus on Stealth checks.</p>
					<p><b>Languages: </b>All hobgoblins begin play speaking Common and Goblin. Hobgoblins with high Intelligence scores can choose any of the following bonus languages: Draconic, Dwarven, Infernal, Giant, Orc.</p>
					<p><b><u>End Note: </u></b><b>** </b>- These links reference Fantasy Grounds library modules - <b><i>Other Abilities </i></b>are links to Universal Monster Rules in a Bestiary Module, and <b><i>Feats </i></b>are links to Core/Basic Rules modules. Relevant modules must be activated for these links to operate.</p>
				</text>
				<token type="token">tokens/Hobgoblin.png@Pathfinder Bestiary</token>
				<treasure type="string">NPC Gear (studded leather armor, light steel shield, longsword, longbow with 20 arrows, other treasure)</treasure>
				<type type="string">LE Medium humanoid (goblinoid)</type>
				<willsave type="number">1</willsave>
				<wisdom type="number">12</wisdom>
				<xp type="number">200</xp>
			</id-00005>
			<id-00006>
				<ac type="string">15, touch 15, flatfooted 12 (+3 Dex, +2 size)</ac>
				<alignment type="string">N</alignment>
				<atk type="string">talon +5 (1d4-2)</atk>
				<babgrp type="string">Base Atk +0; CMB +1; CMD 9</babgrp>
				<charisma type="number">7</charisma>
				<constitution type="number">11</constitution>
				<cr type="number">0.33</cr>
				<dexterity type="number">17</dexterity>
				<environment type="string">temperate forests</environment>
				<feats type="string">Weapon Finesse</feats>
				<fortitudesave type="number">2</fortitudesave>
				<fullatk type="string">2 talons +5 (1d4-2)</fullatk>
				<hd type="string">1d8</hd>
				<hp type="number">4</hp>
				<init type="number">3</init>
				<intelligence type="number">2</intelligence>
				<librarylink type="windowreference">
					<class>npc</class>
					<recordname>..</recordname>
				</librarylink>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Razorcrow</name>
				<organization type="string">solitary or pair</organization>
				<reflexsave type="number">5</reflexsave>
				<senses type="string">low-light vision; Perception +14</senses>
				<skills type="string">Fly +7, Perception +14; Racial Modifier +8 Perception</skills>
				<spacereach type="string">2ft./0ft.</spacereach>
				<speed type="string">10 ft., fly 60 ft. (average)</speed>
				<spelldisplaymode type="string">action</spelldisplaymode>
				<strength type="number">6</strength>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<linklist>
						<link class="imagewindow" recordname="image.hawk@Pathfinder Bestiary">Hawk Image</link>
					</linklist>
					<p><b>Morale</b> The razorcrows fight to the dead</p>
					<p><b>Other Abilities**</b></p>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.lowlightvision@*">Low-light vision</link>
					</linklist>
					<h>Feats**</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referencefeat" recordname="reference.feats.weaponfinesse@*">Weapon Finesse.</link>
					</linklist>
					<p>Falconers prize these majestic birds as trained hunting companions if raised from chicks and properly instructed.</p>
					<p>Presented here are the base animal statistics for all of the most commonly used familiars-of course, these statistics can also be used for normal animals as well. Small animals like these use Dexterity to modify Climb and Swim checks.</p>
					<p><b><u>End Note: </u></b><b>** </b>- These links reference Fantasy Grounds library modules - <b><i>Other Abilities </i></b>are links to Universal Monster Rules in a Bestiary Module, and <b><i>Feats </i></b>are links to Core/Basic Rules modules. Relevant modules must be activated for these links to operate.</p>
				</text>
				<token type="token">tokens/Hawk.png@Pathfinder Bestiary</token>
				<treasure type="string">none</treasure>
				<type type="string">N Tiny animal</type>
				<willsave type="number">2</willsave>
				<wisdom type="number">14</wisdom>
				<xp type="number">135</xp>
			</id-00006>
			<id-00007>
				<ac type="string">15, touch 12 , flat-footed 13(+3 armor, +2 Dex)</ac>
				<atk type="string">bite +5 (1d6+3)</atk>
				<babgrp type="string">Base atk +3; CMB +5; CBD 10</babgrp>
				<charisma type="number">10</charisma>
				<constitution type="number">12</constitution>
				<cr type="number">2</cr>
				<dexterity type="number">15</dexterity>
				<feats type="string">Alertness. Lightning Reflexes</feats>
				<fortitudesave type="number">4</fortitudesave>
				<fullatk type="string">bite +5 (1d6+3)</fullatk>
				<hd type="string">3d12+3</hd>
				<hp type="number">22</hp>
				<init type="number">2</init>
				<intelligence type="number">5</intelligence>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Tatzlwyrm</name>
				<nonid_name type="string">Tatzlwyrn</nonid_name>
				<reflexsave type="number">7</reflexsave>
				<senses type="string">darkvision 60 ft., low-light vision; Perception +4</senses>
				<skills type="string">Climb +10, Hide +7, Listen +6, Move Silently +5, Spot +8;</skills>
				<spacereach type="string">5ft./5ft.</spacereach>
				<specialattacks type="string">improved grab (grp +5), poison, grasp, pounce, rake +4(1d2+1)</specialattacks>
				<specialqualities type="string">immune paralysis, sleep</specialqualities>
				<speed type="string">30ft., climb 30ft.</speed>
				<spelldisplaymode type="string">action</spelldisplaymode>
				<spellset>
				</spellset>
				<strength type="number">14</strength>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<linklist>
						<link class="imagewindow" recordname="image.id-00010">Tatzlwyrm</link>
					</linklist>
					<p>Slithering like a large snake, this creature has the head of a dragon and a pair of clawed arms to help it move along and grasp prey. A sickly green mist wafts from its open maw.</p>
					<h>TACTICS</h>
					<p><b>Before Combat</b> Tatzlwyrms attempt to remain hidden before attacking their prey, preferring areas of dense vegetation. </p>
					<p><b>During Combat</b> Tatzlwyrms attempt to charge as often as possible, using their pounce and rake abilities. Given the opportunity, they grapple their foes and use their poison gasp. </p>
					<p><b>Morale</b> If reduced to 7 or fewer hit points, tatzlwyrms attempt to flee.</p>
					<p></p>
					<h>Special Abilitiies</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referencefeat" recordname="feat.id-00001">Improved Grab</link>
						<link class="referencefeat" recordname="feat.id-00002">Posion Grasp</link>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.pounce@Pathfinder Bestiary">Pounce</link>
					</linklist>
					<h></h>
					<h>ECOLOGY</h>
					<p><b>Environment</b> Any forest </p>
					<p><b>Organization</b> Solitary or nest (2&#150;5) </p>
					<p><b>Treasure </b>Standard </p>
					<p><b>Alignment</b> Always neutral </p>
					<p><b>Advancement</b> 4&#150;6 HD (Medium), 7&#150;13 HD (Large) </p>
					<p><b>Level Adjustment</b> +3</p>
				</text>
				<token type="token">campaign/tokens/tatzlwyrm.png</token>
				<type type="string">N Medium Dragon</type>
				<willsave type="number">1</willsave>
				<wisdom type="number">11</wisdom>
			</id-00007>
			<id-00008>
				<ac type="string">14, touch 10, flat-footed 14</ac>
				<atk type="string">bite +2 (1d8+1)</atk>
				<babgrp type="string">Base Atk +1; CMB +2</babgrp>
				<charisma type="number">1</charisma>
				<constitution type="number">0</constitution>
				<cr type="number">2</cr>
				<dexterity type="number">10</dexterity>
				<feats type="string">Improved Grab, Swallow Whole, Hardness</feats>
				<fortitudesave type="number">0</fortitudesave>
				<fullatk type="string">bite +2 (1d8+1)</fullatk>
				<hd type="string">2d10+20</hd>
				<hp type="number">31</hp>
				<init type="number">0</init>
				<intelligence type="number">0</intelligence>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Ulizmila's Cauldron</name>
				<nonid_name type="string">Cauldron</nonid_name>
				<reflexsave type="number">0</reflexsave>
				<senses type="string">darkvision 60 ft., low-light vision; Perception -5</senses>
				<spacereach type="string">5ft.,5ft.</spacereach>
				<specialattacks type="string">Improved grab (grp +2), swallow whole</specialattacks>
				<specialqualities type="string">hardness 5; Immune construct traits</specialqualities>
				<speed type="string">30 ft.</speed>
				<spelldisplaymode type="string">action</spelldisplaymode>
				<strength type="number">12</strength>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<p></p>
					<h>TACTICS</h>
					<p><b>Before Combat</b> Ulizmila&#146;s cauldron appears to be a perfectly normal cauldron until the objects within the cottage are disturbed, at which point it attacks.</p>
					<p><b>During Combat</b> Ulizmila&#146;s cauldron pursues would-be thieves to the edge of the clearing (it can squeeze through the cottage door). If its opponents flee beyond the glade, the cauldron returns to its place within the cottage and remains inactive until the cottage&#146;s contents are again disturbed.</p>
					<p><b></b></p>
					<h>Special Abilities</h>
					<p><b>Improved Grab (Ex)</b> To use this ability, Ulizmila&#146;s cauldron must hit an opponent of Medium size or smaller with its bite attack. It can then attempt to start a grapple as a free action without provoking an attack of opportunity. If it wins the grapple check, it establishes a hold and can attempt to swallow the opponent the following round.</p>
					<p><b>Swallow Whole (Ex)</b> When Ulizmila&#146;s cauldron begins its turn with a grappled opponent in its &#147;mouth,&#148; it can swallow that opponent with a successful grapple check. Once inside, the opponent takes 1d4 points of nonlethal damage per round from the cauldron&#146;s wild movements. A swallowed creature can cut its way out by using a light weapon to deal 10 points of damage to the cauldron&#146;s interior gizzard (AC 15; hardness 5). Once the creature exits, the stone of the cauldron reforms, closing the hole; another swallowed opponent must fight its own way out. Ulizmila&#146;s cauldron interior can hold 1 Medium, 2 Small, 4 Tiny, 8 Diminutive, or 32 Fine or smaller opponents.</p>
					<p><b>Hardness (Ex)</b> Ulizmila&#146;s cauldron has hardness 5 due to its deteriorated condition.</p>
					<p></p>
					<h>Features</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referencefeat" recordname="feat.id-00001">Improved Grab</link>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.swallowwhole@Pathfinder Bestiary">Swallow Whole</link>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.hardness@Pathfinder Bestiary">Hardness&#10;</link>
					</linklist>
				</text>
				<token type="token">tokens/Medium/c.png@Letter Tokens</token>
				<type type="string">N Medium Construct</type>
				<willsave type="number">-5</willsave>
				<wisdom type="number">1</wisdom>
			</id-00008>
			<id-00009>
				<atk type="string">Atk +5 (1d6 debirs) ;multiple targets (drops 1d4 pieces of debris on each target in the room)</atk>
				<charisma type="number">10</charisma>
				<constitution type="number">10</constitution>
				<cr type="number">1</cr>
				<dexterity type="number">10</dexterity>
				<fortitudesave type="number">0</fortitudesave>
				<hp type="number">0</hp>
				<init type="number">0</init>
				<intelligence type="number">10</intelligence>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Falling Debris Trap</name>
				<npctype type="string">Trap</npctype>
				<reflexsave type="number">0</reflexsave>
				<reset type="string">none</reset>
				<senses type="string">Search DC 10; Disable Device DC 15</senses>
				<spelldisplaymode type="string">action</spelldisplaymode>
				<strength type="number">10</strength>
				<text type="formattedtext">
				</text>
				<token type="token">tokens/Medium/t.png@Letter Tokens</token>
				<trigger type="string">touch</trigger>
				<type type="string">mechanical</type>
				<willsave type="number">0</willsave>
				<wisdom type="number">10</wisdom>
			</id-00009>
			<id-00011>
				<ac type="string">17, touch 14, flat-footed 14 (+2 armor, +3 Dex, +1 natural, +1 size)</ac>
				<alignment type="string">LE</alignment>
				<atk type="string">masterwork shortsword +3 (1d4/19-20); ranged dagger +5 (1d3/19-20)</atk>
				<babgrp type="string">Base Atk +1; CMB -3; CMD 10</babgrp>
				<charisma type="number">8</charisma>
				<constitution type="number">11</constitution>
				<cr type="number">2</cr>
				<dexterity type="number">17</dexterity>
				<environment type="string">temperate underground or deep forest</environment>
				<feats type="string">Improved Initative</feats>
				<fortitudesave type="number">0</fortitudesave>
				<fullatk type="string">masterwork shortsword +3 (1d4/19-20); ranged dagger +5 (1d3/19-20)</fullatk>
				<hd type="string">2d6</hd>
				<hp type="number">9</hp>
				<init type="number">7</init>
				<intelligence type="number">10</intelligence>
				<languages type="string">Draconic</languages>
				<librarylink type="windowreference">
					<class>npc</class>
					<recordname>..</recordname>
				</librarylink>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Gurtlekep</name>
				<nonid_name type="string">Kobold</nonid_name>
				<organization type="string">solitary, gang (2-4), nest (5-30 plus equal number of noncombatants, 1 sergeant of 3rd level per 20 adults, and 1 leader of 4th-6th level), or tribe (31-300 plus 35% noncombatants, 1 sergeant of 3rd level per 20 adults, 2 lieutenants of 4th level, 1 leader of 6th-8th level, and 5-16 dire rats)</organization>
				<raceclass type="string">Kobold warrior 1</raceclass>
				<reflexsave type="number">6</reflexsave>
				<senses type="string">darkvision 60 ft.; perception +6</senses>
				<skills type="string">Craft (trapmaking) +5, Perception +5, Stealth +8; Racial Modifiers +2 Craft (trapmaking), Open Lock +5, Survival +1, Tumble +8</skills>
				<spacereach type="string">5ft./5ft.</spacereach>
				<specialabilities>
					<crafty-ex>
						<name type="string">Crafty (Ex)</name>
						<text type="formattedtext">
							<p>Craft (trapmaking) and Stealth are always class skills for a kobold.</p>
						</text>
					</crafty-ex>
				</specialabilities>
				<specialattacks type="string">sneak attack; DMG: +1d6</specialattacks>
				<specialqualities type="string">Weaknesses light sensitivity; crafty: trapfinding</specialqualities>
				<speed type="string">30 ft.</speed>
				<spelldisplaymode type="string">action</spelldisplaymode>
				<strength type="number">10</strength>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<linklist>
						<link class="imagewindow" recordname="image.kobold@Pathfinder Bestiary">Kobold Image</link>
					</linklist>
					<frame>This short, reptilian humanoid has scaled skin, a snout filled with tiny teeth, and a long tail.</frame>
					<p><b>Race, Class and Level: </b>Kobold rogue 2</p>
					<h>TACTICS</h>
					<p><b>Before Combat</b> If aware of the PCs, Gurtlekep hides under the bed, gaining total cover. The PCs can make opposed Listen checks to hear Gurtlekep before he strikes, allowing them to act in the surprise round.</p>
					<p><b>During Combat</b> Gurtlekep uses the cramped space to his advantage whenever possible, preventing others from entering the room. He focuses all of his attacks on the PC with the least armor first.</p>
					<p><b>Morale</b> If dropped to 3 or fewer hit points, Gurtlekep attempts to flee through a hole in the wall leading into the hallway. This hole is 5 feet above the bed, requiring a single DC 10 Climb check to scale. Once outside, Gurtlekep attempts to flee to warn Greypelt and the kobolds below.</p>
					<p></p>
					<h>Special Abilities</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="..specialabilities.crafty-ex">Crafty (Ex)</link>
					</linklist>
					<h>Other Abilities**</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.darkvision@*">Darkvision 60 ft.</link>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.lightsensitivity@*">Light sensitivity</link>
					</linklist>
					<h>Feats**</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referencefeat" recordname="reference.feats.skillfocus@*">Skill Focus (Perception).</link>
					</linklist>
					<p>Kobolds are creatures of the dark, found most commonly in enormous underground warrens or the dark corners of the forest where the sun is unable to reach. Due to their physical similarities, kobolds loudly proclaim themselves the scions of dragonkind, destined to rule the earth beneath the wings of their great god-cousins, but most dragons have little use for the obnoxious pests.</p>
					<p>While they may speak loudly of divine right and manifest destiny, kobolds are keenly aware of their own weakness. Cowards and schemers, they never fight fair if they can help it, instead setting up ambushes and doublecrosses, holing up in their warrens behind countless crude but ingenious traps, or rolling over the enemy in vast, yipping hordes.</p>
					<p>Kobold coloration varies even among siblings from the same egg clutch, ranging through the colors of the chromatic dragons, with red being the most common but white, green, blue, and black kobolds not unheard of.</p>
					<h>Kobold Characters</h>
					<p>Kobolds are defined by their class levels-they do not possess racial Hit Dice. A kobold with NPC class levels takes a -3 penalty to its CR (rather than the normal -2 penalty). All kobolds have the following racial traits.</p>
					<p><b>-4 Strength, +2 Dexterity, -2 Constitution: </b>Kobolds are fast but weak.</p>
					<p><b>Small: </b>Kobolds are Small and gain a +1 size bonus to their AC, a +1 size bonus on attack rolls, a -1 penalty to their CMB and CMD, and a +4 size bonus on Stealth checks.</p>
					<p><b>Normal Speed: </b>Kobolds have a base speed of 30 feet.</p>
					<p><b>Darkvision: </b>Kobolds can see in the dark up to 60 feet.</p>
					<p><b>Armor: </b>Kobolds have a +1 natural armor bonus.</p>
					<p><b>Crafty: </b>Kobolds gain a +2 racial bonus on Craft (trapmaking), Perception, and Profession (miner) checks. Craft (trapmaking) and Stealth are always class skills for a kobold.</p>
					<p><b>Weakness: </b>Light sensitivity (see page 301).</p>
					<p><b>Languages: </b>Kobolds begin play speaking only Draconic. Kobolds who have high Intelligence scores can choose any of the following bonus languages: Common, Dwarven, Gnome, and Undercommon.</p>
					<p><b><u>End Note: </u></b><b>** </b>- These links reference Fantasy Grounds library modules - <b><i>Other Abilities </i></b>are links to Universal Monster Rules in a Bestiary Module, and <b><i>Feats </i></b>are links to Core/Basic Rules modules. Relevant modules must be activated for these links to operate.</p>
				</text>
				<token type="token">tokens/Kobold.png@Pathfinder Bestiary</token>
				<treasure type="string">NPC gear (leather armor, spear, sling, other treasure)</treasure>
				<type type="string">LE Small humanoid (reptilian)</type>
				<willsave type="number">1</willsave>
				<wisdom type="number">12</wisdom>
				<xp type="number">100</xp>
			</id-00011>
			<id-00013>
				<ac type="string">15, touch 13, flat-footed 12 (+3 Dex, +2 natural)</ac>
				<alignment type="string">NE</alignment>
				<atk type="string">bite +8 (1d6+4 plus trip)</atk>
				<babgrp type="string">Base Atk +6; CMB +8; CMD 19 (23 vs. trip)</babgrp>
				<charisma type="number">10</charisma>
				<constitution type="number">15</constitution>
				<cr type="number">3</cr>
				<dexterity type="number">17</dexterity>
				<environment type="string">temperate forests and plains</environment>
				<feats type="string">Iron Will, Power Attack, Track</feats>
				<fortitudesave type="number">9</fortitudesave>
				<fullatk type="string">bite +8  (1d6+4 plus trip)</fullatk>
				<hd type="string">4d10+2d8+12</hd>
				<hp type="number">43</hp>
				<init type="number">3</init>
				<intelligence type="number">8</intelligence>
				<isidentified type="number">0</isidentified>
				<languages type="string">Common, Goblin</languages>
				<librarylink type="windowreference">
					<class>npc</class>
					<recordname>..</recordname>
				</librarylink>
				<locked type="number">1</locked>
				<name type="string">Greypelt</name>
				<nonid_name type="string">Worg</nonid_name>
				<organization type="string">solitary, pair, or pack (3-11)</organization>
				<reflexsave type="number">7</reflexsave>
				<senses type="string">darkvision 60 ft., low-light vision, scent; Perception +11</senses>
				<skills type="string">Perception +11, Stealth +9, Survival +5; Racial Modifiers +2 Perception, +2 Survival</skills>
				<spacereach type="string">5ft./5ft.</spacereach>
				<specialattacks type="string">trip (+2)</specialattacks>
				<speed type="string">50 ft.</speed>
				<spelldisplaymode type="string">action</spelldisplaymode>
				<spellset>
				</spellset>
				<strength type="number">15</strength>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<linklist>
						<link class="imagewindow" recordname="image.id-00004">Graypelt</link>
					</linklist>
					<frame>This unusually large wolf has an evil, almost intelligent light shining in its deep red eyes.</frame>
					<h>Other Abilities**</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.darkvision@*">Darkvision 60 ft.</link>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.lowlightvision@*">Low-light vision</link>
						<link class="referenceclassability" recordname="reference.universalmonsterrules.scent@*">Scent</link>
					</linklist>
					<h>Feats**</h>
					<linklist>
						<link class="referencefeat" recordname="reference.feats.ironwill@Pathfinder Core Rules">Iron Will</link>
						<link class="referencefeat" recordname="reference.feats.powerattack@Pathfinder Core Rules">Power Attack</link>
					</linklist>
					<p>Worgs are oversized, evil, intelligent wolves often found dwelling amid goblins or other savage races. A typical worg has gray or black fur, stands 3 feet tall at the shoulder, and weighs 300 pounds.</p>
					<p>Worgs hunt in packs, running down and surrounding their prey like common wolves, but their intelligence and ability to speak make them better at coordinating their attacks. They sometimes use one packmate as a decoy, pretending to be a humanoid calling for help in order to lure intelligent prey into an ambush. Worgs that travel with goblins often allow them to ride on their backs, but in such situations it is usually the worg that is the master, not the rider.</p>
					<p><b><u>End Note: </u></b><b>** </b>- These links reference Fantasy Grounds library modules - <b><i>Other Abilities </i></b>are links to Universal Monster Rules in a Bestiary Module, and <b><i>Feats </i></b>are links to Core/Basic Rules modules. Relevant modules must be activated for these links to operate.</p>
				</text>
				<token type="token">campaign/tokens/greypelt.png</token>
				<treasure type="string">incidental</treasure>
				<type type="string">CE Medium magical beast</type>
				<willsave type="number">4</willsave>
				<wisdom type="number">12</wisdom>
				<xp type="number">600</xp>
			</id-00013>
		</category>
	</npc>
	<options>
		<public />
		<REVL type="string">on</REVL>
		<TBOX type="string">on</TBOX>
		<TNAM type="string">tooltip</TNAM>
	</options>
	<partysheet>
		<public />
	</partysheet>
	<quest>
	</quest>
	<specialability>
	</specialability>
	<storytemplate>
	</storytemplate>
	<tables>
		<category name="Hollow's Last Hope" baseicon="0" decalicon="0">
			<id-00001>
				<description type="string">Random Encounters while exploring the vale</description>
				<dice type="dice"></dice>
				<hiderollresults type="number">1</hiderollresults>
				<mod type="number">0</mod>
				<name type="string">Random Encounter In DarkMoon Vale</name>
				<notes type="formattedtext">
				</notes>
				<output type="string">story</output>
				<resultscols type="number">1</resultscols>
				<table_positionoffset type="number">0</table_positionoffset>
				<tablerows>
					<id-00001>
						<fromrange type="number">1</fromrange>
						<results>
							<id-00001>
								<result type="string">Foul Tracks</result>
								<resultlink type="windowreference">
									<class></class>
									<recordname></recordname>
								</resultlink>
							</id-00001>
						</results>
						<torange type="number">1</torange>
					</id-00001>
					<id-00002>
						<fromrange type="number">2</fromrange>
						<results>
							<id-00001>
								<result type="string">Dead Fey</result>
								<resultlink type="windowreference">
									<class></class>
									<recordname></recordname>
								</resultlink>
							</id-00001>
						</results>
						<torange type="number">2</torange>
					</id-00002>
					<id-00003>
						<fromrange type="number">3</fromrange>
						<results>
							<id-00001>
								<result type="string">Woodsmen</result>
								<resultlink type="windowreference">
									<class></class>
									<recordname></recordname>
								</resultlink>
							</id-00001>
						</results>
						<torange type="number">3</torange>
					</id-00003>
					<id-00004>
						<fromrange type="number">5</fromrange>
						<results>
							<id-00001>
								<result type="string">Wyvern Sighting</result>
								<resultlink type="windowreference">
									<class></class>
									<recordname></recordname>
								</resultlink>
							</id-00001>
						</results>
						<torange type="number">5</torange>
					</id-00004>
					<id-00005>
						<fromrange type="number">6</fromrange>
						<results>
							<id-00001>
								<result type="string">Kobold Shaman</result>
								<resultlink type="windowreference">
									<class></class>
									<recordname></recordname>
								</resultlink>
							</id-00001>
						</results>
						<torange type="number">6</torange>
					</id-00005>
					<id-00006>
						<fromrange type="number">7</fromrange>
						<results>
							<id-00001>
								<result type="string">Giant Mosquito</result>
								<resultlink type="windowreference">
									<class></class>
									<recordname></recordname>
								</resultlink>
							</id-00001>
						</results>
						<torange type="number">7</torange>
					</id-00006>
					<id-00007>
						<fromrange type="number">8</fromrange>
						<results>
							<id-00001>
								<result type="string">Hunter's Snare</result>
								<resultlink type="windowreference">
									<class></class>
									<recordname></recordname>
								</resultlink>
							</id-00001>
						</results>
						<torange type="number">8</torange>
					</id-00007>
					<id-00008>
						<fromrange type="number">4</fromrange>
						<results>
							<id-00001>
								<result type="string">Glowmold</result>
								<resultlink type="windowreference">
									<class></class>
									<recordname></recordname>
								</resultlink>
							</id-00001>
						</results>
						<torange type="number">4</torange>
					</id-00008>
					<id-00009>
						<fromrange type="number">9</fromrange>
						<results>
							<id-00001>
								<result type="string">Giant Moorsnake</result>
								<resultlink type="windowreference">
									<class></class>
									<recordname></recordname>
								</resultlink>
							</id-00001>
						</results>
						<torange type="number">9</torange>
					</id-00009>
					<id-00010>
						<fromrange type="number">10</fromrange>
						<results>
							<id-00001>
								<result type="string">Wolves</result>
								<resultlink type="windowreference">
									<class></class>
									<recordname></recordname>
								</resultlink>
							</id-00001>
						</results>
						<torange type="number">10</torange>
					</id-00010>
				</tablerows>
			</id-00001>
		</category>
	</tables>
	<treasureparcels>
	</treasureparcels>
	<windowsaver>
		<id-00007>
			<masterindex type="string">encounter</masterindex>
		</id-00007>
		<id-00012>
			<masterindex type="string">tables</masterindex>
		</id-00012>
		<id-00021>
			<masterindex type="string">quest</masterindex>
		</id-00021>
		<id-00067>
			<masterindex type="string">feat</masterindex>
		</id-00067>
		<id-00098>
			<masterindex type="string">item</masterindex>
		</id-00098>
	</windowsaver>
	<windowsaverdesktop>
	</windowsaverdesktop>
</root>
